<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html</id>
    <title>gsyx::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-05T09:32:20.087Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11 正式版发布，升级后一定不要错过这些新特性]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69072</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69072"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[北京时间 10 月 5 日，微软发布了其下一代桌面操作系统 Windows 11 正式版，和 Windows 10 不同的是，Windows 11 具有更为现代的设计风格，完全替代传统控制面板的「设置」工具，全新的小部件等新工具，无论在设计还是功能上都让人耳目一新。
少数派整理了 Windows 10 正式版中值得关注的系统新特性，希望可以帮助广大的 Windows 用户可以更加熟悉这个全新设计的「下一代 Windows」。
编注：无论是全新安装还是升级到 Windows 11，都请先对重要的数据进行备份，对于不在「官方支持硬件」范围内的设备，强行安装 Windows 11 可能会出现无可预估的系统故障和 Bug，请在安装前三思而后行，也可以通过虚拟机的形式进行尝鲜，不建议用在生产环境中。
我的电脑能升级/安装 Windows 11 吗？

和 Windows 10 具有较高的硬件兼容性有所不同的是，Windows 11 对于硬件设备有着较高的要求，目前微软给出的 官方硬件要求 如下：

需要 1GHz 或更快的支持 64 位的处理器（双核或多核）或系统单芯片(SoC)；
4GB 内存；
64GB 或更大的存储设备；
支持 UEFI 安全启动；
受信任的平台模块(TPM)版本 2.0；
支持 DirectX 12 或更高版本，支持 WDDM 2.0 驱动程序；
对角线长大于 9 英寸的高清 (720p) 显示屏，每个颜色通道为 8 位。

虽然在硬件需求中并没有专门说明，但微软却单独给出了官方的支持处理器型号支持列表，其中 Intel 的处理器 最低型号需要至少八代酷睿处理器以及同架构的奔腾、赛扬、志强以及 Atom 处理器。而 AMD 方面，最低支持的 CPU 型号为锐龙 2000 及对应同架构的霄龙处理器、速龙处理器、线程撕裂者处理器。

从今天开始对于所有支持的设备，…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>化学心情下2</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[城市收藏夹 · 香港：两年不见，甚是想念]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/68195</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/68195"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T03:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[一个城市的魅力不全是它的历史、文化或自然风光，也有不少惊喜往往来自那些只有当地人才知晓的隐蔽深巷。而「城市收藏夹」是我们征集来自世界各地 Matrix 社区作者共同维护的一个长期话题，我们会邀请大家分享自己所在城市或家乡的美食或玩乐目的地。
大众点评可能会让你踩坑，但我们不会。

今年八月份，我前往香港，作为一名学生，开始了新生活。
说到香港，真的很感慨，因为太久没来，以至于对它感到有点陌生了。（许万里同学说的，我觉得也非常能描述我的心境，所以直接搬来用了。）
作为一个广州人，我基本上每年都会来一次。上一次来香港是 2019 年的 6 月，那一次是来考试，所以并没有去什么地方，除了在考场考试，大部分时间都在酒店里备考了。离开香港时，本以为找个假期再来一次很容易，没想到，匆匆一别，已是两年的时间。这两年的时间里，香港和我自己都经历了很多，以至于出发前我对于这个曾经感到无比熟悉的城市竟然产生了一些茫然：究竟，香港现在是什么样子呢？我也很想知道。
沙田 车公庙附近
怎么去香港
在开始讲述我的港漂生活之前，想先和大家分享一下我来港前的各项准备工作。
租房
在办理签证之前，我们需要先找好住处。因为港校的研究生基本上不能分配到宿舍，所以绝大部分的学生都需要自己找房子租。
在香港，非本地研究生租房基本上有三种选择，分别是租村屋、租普通商品房和长租酒店。
村屋
定义：指位于学校附近村子里的别墅，既可以整套出租，也可以分开出租给不同人。
优点：价格会相对低廉。和普通商品房相比，相同价格下往往能获得更大的个人使用空间。有的村屋还会配有院子。地理上通常会更加靠近学校（对于在一些位置稍微偏僻学校就读的学生会更有吸引力）。
缺点：因为位置偏僻，通常配套设施（交通、饮食、娱乐）不是很好。
适合人群：耐得住寂寞，预算有限，对私人空间比较有要求，动手能力较强的同学。
普通商品房
定义：指普通的商品房，可以…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hermanchannn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[有没有简单易用的审核、审批工具？橙子审批]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39996</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/chengzi-shenpi-wechat-miniapp/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T02:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[没选丁丁、企业微信的审批。因为是合作单位人员没法拉到企业群。找到一个很好的微信小程序，名字是橙子审批，不用外单位人员另外装 App 了。操作流程合适，公众号提醒审批操作。]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use the Traceroute and Ping Commands to Troubleshoot Network Connectivity Issues]]></title>
        <id>5fff3ec998be260817e495ee</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/traceroute-and-ping/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T23:46:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ping and traceroute are common commands you can use to troubleshoot network problems.  Ping is a simple command that can test the reachability of a device on the network.  Traceroute is a command you use to 'trace' the route that a packet takes when traveling to its destination. It's useful]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Your Own Developer Portfolio Website with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>6154775964aefe07d3fa0b7d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-a-developer-portfolio-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T20:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone needs websites and web applications these days. So there are many opportunities for you if you work as a web developer.  But if you want to get a web developer job, you'll need a good portfolio website to showcase your skills and experience.  In this tutorial, I'll discuss some]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quickly Testing CSS Fallbacks]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=353179</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/quickly-testing-css-fallbacks/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T19:15:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dumb trick alert! 
Not all browsers support all features. Say you want to write a fallback for browsers that doesn’t support CSS Grid. Not very common these days, but it’s just to illustrate a point.
You could write the supporting …
The post Quickly Testing CSS Fallbacks appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the OSI Model? Computer Networking for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>613b97f1852f4307d372b637</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/osi-model-computer-networking-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:27:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you will learn about the core concepts of the Open Systems Interconnections (OSI) model in a simple and easy way. As a developer, it's a good idea to learn how things work "under the hood". That way you understand what your code and the tools you use]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is UX Design? User Experience Design Explained in Plain English]]></title>
        <id>61063c1d3306a507d1bfbfca</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/user-experience-design-what-does-a-ux-designer-do/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:21:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have heard of the term User Experience or UX design. But what does it mean exactly? In this article, I will explain what UX design is and talk about how to become a UX designer.  What is UX design?The term User Experience refers to how users interact]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animation Techniques for Adding and Removing Items From a Stack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352819</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/animation-techniques-for-adding-and-removing-items-from-a-stack/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T14:05:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Animating elements with CSS can either be quite easy or quite difficult depending on what you are trying to do. Changing the background color of a button when you hover over it? Easy. Animating the position and size of an …
The post Animation Techniques for Adding and Removing Items From a Stack appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Courtney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ShopTalk Goes Video]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352857</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/shoptalk-goes-video/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T14:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dave and I slapped up a little videos section of the ShopTalk website. Twelve so far! They are short-ish, between 10-20 minutes, each focused on one fairly specific thing. We’re kinda just dipping our toes here — we don’t …
The post ShopTalk Goes Video appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBDown – 命令行式 Bilibili 哔哩哔哩视频下载器，支持番剧全集、杜比视界]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39988</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/bbdown-down-bilibili-video/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BBDown 是一款命令行式，仅针对 Bilibili 网站的视频下载器，支持杜比视界/杜比全景声下载，可下载番剧全集、指定清晰度、下载外挂字幕、多线程下载、支持 Aria2c，可在 Windows、]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build An Expandable Accessible Gallery]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/build-expandable-accessible-gallery/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be looking at how to set up a gallery that is expandable as well as accessible with a few tips and tricks along the way. Let’s get started!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Silvestar Bistrović)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[派评 | 近期值得关注的 App]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69105</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69105"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T08:31:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[本期《派评》的内容有：

📷 iOS 专业相机应用 NOMO RAW 迎来大版本更新。
🥛 除了记录喝水还不够，HiWater 还想帮你控制热量。
📈 iWork 办公三件套迎来大更新，让线上协作更加便利。
……

你可以通过文章目录快速跳转到你感兴趣的内容。如果发现了其它感兴趣的 App 或者关注的话题，也欢迎在评论区和我们进行讨论。
不容错过的新 App
虽然少数派一直在为大家发发现和介绍各平台上的优质 App，但仍有不少设计、功能、交互、体验都非常优秀的 App，还没有被我们发掘和介绍。它们可能是一款老 App，也可能是近期上架的新 App，我们会在这里介绍给你。
HiWater：光记录喝水还不够，控制热量也很重要

平台：iOS / iPadOS
关键词：饮水记录、健康追踪

@Vanilla：作为老牌喝水应用 WaterMinder 的用户，我对这款 App 已经非常满意。可是，当我看到 HiWater 后，我才后知后觉得发现 WaterMinder 缺少了点什么，那就是对摄入热量的提醒。
在「今日」标签页，HiWater 展示了当日的饮水进度和详细的记录历史，这是它与其它喝水应用相同的功能。不过，每日补水目标下方的饮水金字塔就非常有意思了，它将常见饮品分为 6 个健康等级，用来衡量各类饮品的摄入比例。金字塔底端的白水是健康补水的首选，而位于顶端的饮品应加以控制。也就是说，我每天除了要完成饮水数量的目标，还要注重摄入水分的质量，如果热量太高导致超标，也是一件得不偿失的事情。

在设置界面中，我可以调整「饮水金字塔」的比例：对正常用户来说白水的比例要大于等于 60%，而对于需要控制热量输入的人群来说白水的比例要大于等于 70%，大家可以各取所需。在「饮品目录」标签页中，我可以查询到每一类饮品每 100 毫升所含的热量，根据热量大小从 LV1 到 LV6 分门别…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>少数派编辑部</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[平衡与极致：iPhone 13 & iPhone 13 Pro Max 体验]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69097</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69097"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T03:21:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[每年 iPhone 推出新款之后，如何选择一定是个热门话题。一边是尺寸、功能都「刚刚好」的数字系列，一边是代表着最强移动设备的 Pro 系列，当然价格也是最强。尤其是去年 iPhone 12 mini 的加入，让本就难做的这道选择题变得更难了。
今年我有机会拿到了 iPhone 13 和 iPhone 13 Pro Max 二台设备，并且也在之前 上手体验 了 iPhone 13 全系列的 4 款机型，对于不同型号 iPhone 的使用体验，以及如何选择的问题，也来聊聊我的看法。
关联阅读：荧幕、影像、性能处处 Pro，一台没有「短板」的好手机：iPhone 13 Pro 体验
手感也许「没那么重要」
iPhone 12 mini 的出现，如同手机行业的一场「文艺复兴」：极致的尺寸设计、极佳的握持体验，不少人曾日思夜想的「小屏旗舰」，似乎在这里有了答案。不过，经过一年时间的检验，这台尺寸 mini 的 iPhone，似乎没有许多人当初想得那么好：出色的尺寸设计，牺牲的必然是电池续航；极佳的握持体验之外，好像也无更多优势可言。
iPhone 13 mini
相反地，在与 iPhone 13 相伴的一周之内，我重新找到了久违的轻松体验：与 iPhone 13 Pro 尺寸相仿的同时，轻了 30 克的手感称为减负毫不为过。作为 Pro 系列 iPhone 的多年用户，上手 iPhone 13 之后，我注意到了一个之前没有发现的细节：铝金属边框相比不锈钢边框，除了不留指纹之外，更加「亲切」的触感对于握持体验而言也有提升；如果要用词语来形容这种「亲切感」，「光滑」与「亲肤」也许较为准确。反观 iPhone 13 Pro 系列，手术级不锈钢边框不论质感还是触感虽然已经足够优秀，但是相比之下摸起来也确实有点「生涩」了。
iPhone 13
当然，iPhone 13 的握持体验，也让人挑不…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>waychane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NohBoard – 键盘可视化程序，在屏幕上显示按键[Windows]]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39980</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/nohboard-keyboard-visualization/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T07:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NohBoard 是一款键盘可视化程序，它能改在屏幕上显示整个虚拟键盘，并实时、动态、高亮显示按下的键。有多种虚拟键盘布局（游戏键盘等）、多种皮肤。搭配 OBS 可用于直播、游戏直播、@Appinn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[与保险「共舞」多年悟出的 5 条心得，或许能让你少走弯路]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69091</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69091"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T07:36:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[编注：本篇文章为「年轻人的第一份保险指南」的后记。「保险怎么买，才不花冤枉钱」是许多年轻人共有的困惑。希望用合理的资金投入，构建最佳的保险配置，是我们相同的诉求。通过这份「年轻人的第一份保险指南」，希望能为你解答这些问题。
 
大家好，我是关哥，感谢你和我一起走进了保险的世界。
《年轻人的第一份保险指南》的正文已经全部更新完成了。课程里我们密集地介绍了很多知识点，暂时消化不了也很正常。我希望这套课程，先帮你接触到一个大致的体系，即使对它的概念是模糊的，也没有关系。有些细节，是在我们真正要做决策时，才能体会到的区别。
不知道有多少人会跟随课程，一路走到这一章节。但如果你看到这里了，我想继续和你分享几条建议，这也是我在和保险多年的「共舞」中，感悟出的道理。
通过提问来学习
其实，我自己的保险入门和精进，本来就是在回答问题中完成的。
我在少数派的播客中，和老麦聊到了我过去的经历。如果你听过这期节目就会知道，我既接触过大量的保险从业人员，也面对面接触了很多银行客户，同时，也一直在做培训。我每天的工作内容，就是解答各种各样的问题。包括写公众号、做保险科普的这些年，我也在线回答了有几万条留言。
有人对保险的规则充满疑惑：「为什么医生说我没事，但保险却不保？」「为什么我父亲做了大手术，重疾险也不给赔？」
有人寻求配置保险的具体建议：「我到底要不要选择身负责任？」「别人给我推荐了一个保险，说是收益不错，比存银行划算，是真的吗？」
甚至还有人仍对保险充满负面的看法：「买的没有卖的精！」「我想买，可是觉得理赔太难了。」
我对保险的理解，就是在替别人寻找这些答案的过程中，逐渐得到了丰富和完善。从一个一个独立的知识点，构建起了立体多元的知识体系。同时，也看到了人性和思维模式的多样性。
从一个人的提问中，其实能看出很多东西。对保险的认知在什么程度？关心的问题是什么？思考问题的逻辑在哪里？
从专业角度…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>关哥Emma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 250 Best Free Online Courses of All Time – A Data-Driven Analysis [2021 Edition]]]></title>
        <id>5f9c98a3740569d1a4ca1b33</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/best-online-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T04:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every year Class Central releases a list of the Best Free Online Courses Of All Time, based on tens of thousands of user reviews. This year, thanks to a growing number of reviews, I've expanded the list from 200 to 250 courses. For close to ten years, well-known and well-respected]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[看什么 · 特别篇丨秋天到了，我最想生活在这 10 部电影里]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69093</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69093"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T04:20:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[导语
伴着淅淅沥沥秋雨而来的除了骤降的气温，还有秋日独特的浓郁色调，我们去公园散步，到山间露营，品尝时令美味，也许每年你都有一份长长的「秋日必做清单」，毕竟没人想错过秋天短暂的赏味期限。
本片单共 10 部影视作品，大都是发生在秋天的故事，有人恋爱，有人离别，也有人过着平淡却美好的日常。你的秋天发生着怎样的故事，你最喜欢在秋天做些什么？欢迎在评论区分享和讨论 🙋，我们会选取一则优质评论，送上少数派周边一份 🎁！
之后每个月「看什么」栏目都会推出不同主题的特辑，关注每周新片的同时，也和大家一起回顾过往经典。
TL;DR

[电影] 秋天的故事、[电影] 秋天的童话
[电影] 蒂莫西的奇异生活、[动画] 狼与香辛料、[电影] 小森林 夏秋篇
[电影] 转转、[电影] 去见瀑布、[电影] 晚秋
[电影] 当哈利遇到莎莉、[电影] 秋天里的春光

根据读者反馈，如果推荐语涉及剧透（对故事核心、暗线、伏笔、结局等关键要素的透露），我们会在对应作品的标题前增加 🔦 的 Emoji。
如果你喜欢我们的内容，希望它持续更新，或是有任何建议，就请留言和充电吧~ 你们的支持将是我们的重要动力！

[电影] 秋天的故事

关键词：剧情 / 爱情
片长：112 分钟；豆瓣链接
观看渠道：哔哩哔哩

当生命这场旅行走到秋天，方能结出最香醇的葡萄果实。

@利兹与青鸟 ：《秋天的故事》是法国导演侯麦「四季故事系列」的最后一部，侯麦眼中的秋天，是丰收的、喜悦的、金色的季节，单身的马嘉利经营的葡萄园迎来了收成旺季，她的好友伊莎贝拉的女儿即将举行婚礼，人们在秋日午后洒满金色阳光的庭院树下，谈论着生活与爱情。
侯麦热衷于展示人物在道德边缘的试探，但总能把看似狗血的情节处理得轻盈自然、不落俗套。《秋天的故事》聚焦于中年男女的情感生活，全片情节可以简单概括为「一厢情愿为好友介绍对象后，产生的种种误会」：马嘉…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>少数派编辑部</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[不读可以先收藏 03 | 这些好文让你的假期更充实]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69082</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69082"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T08:09:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[不读可以先收藏
让有价值的内容保持生命力，是对少数派作者分享和创作精神的肯定，对刚刚接触少数派的读者而言，这些内容也是方便他们直达少数派内容和 Matrix 社区核心价值的钥匙。
在这个不定期更新的栏目中，少数派编辑部将人工挑选过去一段时间内值得重读和收藏的文章，这些内容凝聚了作者的耕耘和读者的肯定，应该能为想读好内容的你献上一份数字时代的「合订本」。

大家好，今天是 2021 年 10 月 2 日。本栏目的第 3 期，我们从上一周期内推荐到首页的 120 篇文章中挑选了 10 篇值得你收藏的好文。
快把文章末尾的收藏按钮用起来吧。
这些文章可以先收藏
看什么 Café丨当我们聊「电影感」的时候，我们在聊些什么？
🔋 充电量：57
作者：利兹与青鸟

无论艺术的形式如何变迁，历史如何循环往复，能够被记住的一定是那些体现着「人」这一主体及其精神世界发展历程的作品，「电影感」的本质不在于高难度的炫技，而是技术背后创作者所想传递的一切信息、观念与情感。
阅读全文>

编辑荐语（北鸮）：「电影感」对大多数人来说只是一个模糊的名词。人们用它描述，用它形容，甚至用它赞赏，但很少有人明明白白地解释出它是什么。这篇文章以希区柯克的《后窗》为主线，将「电影感」中包含的叙事手法、剪辑魔术一点点拆开，以「拉片」的方法深入浅出地为读者解析这一概念。
对于希望将电影看得更深入的人来说，这篇文章是很好的引导。它提供了一种思维方式，让你可以在欣赏电影时，多一层技术与艺术的角度，让电影的欣赏不再局限于词不逮意的感叹。而抛开这一专业层面，本文也可以作为希区柯克经典作品的观影引导，让你从《后窗》开始，逐步体会希区柯克精心构建的恐怖世界。
「看什么 Café」是「本周看什么」的衍生栏目，旨在从一个特定主题或视角为读者提供与电影相关的优质内容，栏目中每篇文章都可以为你的闲暇时光添些乐趣。

吹尽狂沙始到金——…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>少数派编辑部</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Privacy Insights – 谁访问了你的照片和地理位置，7 天内[iOS]]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39977</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/app-privacy-insights/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T03:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[App Privacy Insights 是一款 iOS 上的第三方应用隐私查看工具，它通过统计 iOS 系统中的记录 App 活动数据，显示了每一个应用的隐私权限访问情况，包括访问网络、地理位置、麦]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[一日一技 | 解决 Minecraft 在 M1 Mac 上的 Error 255 报错]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/68830</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/68830"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matrix 首页推荐
Matrix 是少数派的写作社区，我们主张分享真实的产品体验，有实用价值的经验与思考。我们会不定期挑选 Matrix 最优质的文章，展示来自用户的最真实的体验和观点。
文章代表作者个人观点，少数派仅对标题和排版略作修改。

Apple 在去年年底发布了 M1 芯片，这款芯片在性能、功耗、发热方面的表现，都让无数吃瓜网友大为震惊。正好手中的电脑也到了该换机的时候，我瞅准时机，入手了一台 M1 MacBook Air。
等我收到电脑，习惯性安装了最爱的 Minecraft。这时却发现，只有原版游戏可以正常运行，当我给游戏安装 Minecraft 知名第三方 Forge API 之后，游戏在启动时会报错「Error 255」，有时又会报错「GLFW Error 65544」，无法进入游戏界面。根据错误信息可知，两种报错均为相同原因导致。
Error 255GLFW Error 65544
由于我只是一位普普通通的创造模式玩家，失去 Mod 支持，游戏的乐趣就少了很多。为此我不得不暂停我的火柴盒建造计划，苦寻解决方法。
而根据网络中搜索到的各种解决方案，并没有解决我本机 Minecraft 报错的问题，因此我将近半年没有打开游戏。这几天我又按耐不住，结合网友的教程和我自己的一些尝试，非常幸运的解决了游戏报错的问题。如果网上的其他教程同样未能解决你的问题，不妨参考一下这篇文章。
我的解决方法
1.卸载系统当前安装的 Java 版本
打开终端，输入命令 java -version ，查看当前安装的 Java 版本。如果是 Oracle Java ，需要卸载并安装 Zulu Java。
输入命令查询 Java 版本
Oracle Java 不能通过常规方式卸载，需要在官网下载 专用卸载工具。不建议直接删除 Java 路径文件夹，否则 macOS 设置中会残留 Ja…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>JLDUAN</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on React and JavaScript II]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352717</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-react-and-javascript-ii/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T21:09:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How To Use The Vite Build Tool with React — Vite is hot, in part, because it’s based on esbuild and wickedly fast. It’s from Evan You of Vue fame, but it’s not a Vue-specific tool. Here, NARUHODO covers how 
…
The post Links on React and JavaScript II appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the platform]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352867</id>
        <link href="https://elisehe.in/2021/08/22/using-the-platform"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T18:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm certainly not dogmatic about it, but I think if you can pull of a project with literally zero build process, it feels good while working on it and feels very good when you come back to it months/years later and can just pick up and go.
The post Using the platform appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Solve the Problem of Multiple Inheritance in Java]]></title>
        <id>613f8a73852f4307d372cc55</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-solve-multiple-inheritance-in-java/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T14:42:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Java is one of the most popular object-oriented programming languages in use today.  Because it is platform-independent, you will find Java applications on every type of device and every operating system. And because Java is relatively easy to learn, it is one of the first languages that many programmers pick]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working With Built-in GraphQL Directives]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352798</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/working-with-built-in-graphql-directives/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T14:35:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Directives are one of GraphQL’s best — and most unspoken — features.
Let’s explore working with GraphQL’s built-in schema and operation directives that all GraphQL spec compliant APIs must implement. They are extremely useful if you are working with a …
The post Working With Built-in GraphQL Directives appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Barton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Search Functionality In Your Nuxt App Using Algolia InstantSearch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/10/search-functionality-nuxt-app-algolia-instantsearch/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many websites have some sort of search feature because it helps users navigate through their content easily. Implementing it the right way can be tricky and might not give a good user experience. In this tutorial, we will be integrating Algolia, a popular and powerful search service for the best experience on our Nuxt site.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miracle Onyenma)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[本周看什么丨最近值得一看的 7 部作品]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/69083</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/69083"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[☕️ TL;DR

近期佳作推荐：[国产剧] 功勋、[音乐剧] 来自远方、[动画] 蓝色时期、[美剧] 紧急呼救 第五季、[综艺] 最后的赢家、[国产剧] 在希望的田野上、[美剧] 午夜弥撒
几则精彩预告：漫改 TV 动画《鬼灭之刃 花街篇》12 月 5 日开始播出、动画剧集《英雄联盟：双城之战》发布正式中字预告，11 月 6 日上线 Netflix、骨头社制作 Netflix 超能力动画《超级骗子》首曝预告，11 月 25 日上线、《活死人军团》前传《神偷军团》10 月 29 日上线 Netflix
几则影视资讯：奥斯卡最佳外语片《入殓师》中国内地定档 10 月 29 日、Netflix 已正式宣布续订《性爱自修室》第四季、Netflix 真人版《星际牛仔》剧集首曝片头，11 月 19 日播出
🎬 秋日特辑：这 10 部电影，让你不再错过秋天的短暂赏味期 🍁

👀 N 部作品推荐
🇨🇳 大家国庆假期愉快！
根据读者反馈，如果推荐语涉及剧透（对故事核心、暗线、伏笔、结局等关键要素的透露），我们会在对应作品的标题前增加 🔦 的 Emoji。
如有其他建议也欢迎在评论区提出，感谢大家对「看什么」栏目的喜爱和支持。
[国产剧] 功勋

关键词：剧情 / 传记
片长：41 分钟（单集）× 48 集；豆瓣链接
@宇宙浪费指南：《功勋》采用单元创作的模式，全剧分为 8 个单元，讲述 8 位共和国勋章获得者的故事，每个单元各有对应负责的导演，并由郑晓龙担任总导演。
剧集取材于真实故事，用单元剧的形式，将首批八位功勋人物的人生华彩篇章与共和国命运串联起来，更加凸显时代背景下的英雄人物，也更深刻诠释他们忠诚、执着、朴实的人生品格和献身祖国人民的崇高境界。
《功勋》分别讲述了投身国防安全事业的于敏、首倡男女同工同酬的第一届全国人大代表申纪兰、科学家孙家栋、抗美援朝英雄李延年、战斗英…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>少数派编辑部</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion 活动：绑卡送 500 刀，可用 10 年 Personal Pro，完全不扣费]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39981</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/notion-adalovelace-500-usd/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T09:23:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Notion 是著名且好用的在线工具，官方定义为：每个团队一个工作空间，不仅仅是一份文件、一个表格，定制 Notion，让它按照你的方式工作。你可以用 Notion 记笔记，做表格、公司主页、产品线路]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xournal++ – 支持 PDF 注释的手写记事软件[Win/macOS/Linux]]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39971</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/xournal/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T06:27:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xournal++ 是一款支持 PDF 注释的手写记事软件，采用 C++ 语言和 GTK3 编写，支持 Linux、macOS 和 Windows，支持 Wacom Tablets 等设备的笔输入，开]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[笔记文档一把梭——MkDocs 快速上手指南]]></title>
        <id>https://sspai.com/post/68878</id>
        <link href="https://sspai.com/post/68878"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T03:20:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[引言
在无纸化信息处理的流程中，信息输入、信息整理阶段的工具选择已经很多了，雨后春笋般不断浮现的笔记工具让人眼花缭乱。但到了信息输出和展示的环节——例如发表自己的读书心得、思考或是学习笔记，或是为自己的软件项目撰写文档——现有解决方案则总有明显的遗憾之处。
一方面，如果选择语雀、Notion 这样的第三方云端文档平台来存放，定制空间就很有限，且数据始终是寄人篱下。另一方面，如果选择 WordPress 这类 CMS 或近年流行的 Jekyll、Hugo 或是 Hexo 等「静态网站生成器」，随之而来的技术门槛和复杂操作又容易打消人的创作和分享热情。
以我个人为例，我想通过搭建简单的静态网站来很好地展示我在学习编程过程中的所作的笔记、对问题的看法等，将它们作为一个 Cookbook 或系统化的参考文档来使用，同时也兼具美观和可读性。对此，上述主流框架都有些「杀鸡用牛刀」的感觉，那么，有没有更好的方式呢？
我遇见的答案是 MkDocs。
什么是 MkDocs？
MkDocs（Markdown Documents）是一个快速、简单的静态网站生成器，用于将 Markdown 文档组织起来构建成有层次、美观的文档站点。

MkDocs 基于 Python 编写，也贯彻了 Python 里「简洁胜于复杂」的理念，与其他常见的静态网站生成器相比，无需繁琐的环境配置（如 Jekyll 涉及的 Bundler、Gems 等），所有配置都用只有简单的一个配置文件管理，并且当中配置项的内容也仅有一页文档。
MkDocs 见名知意就是为 Markdown 而生，根据 Markdown 格式将内容渲染成美观的文档，并通过目录层级关系对应文档的树状结构，使得当中所有的文档组织分明且层次递进。

此外，简洁不等同于简单，MkDocs 还为「动手能力强」的玩家们提供了扩展的空间：我们可以进一步让更多语法特…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>100gle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility Best Practices for Mobile App Development]]></title>
        <id>611b08a4e884de075217ff23</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/mobile-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T21:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The United States Census Bureau estimates that more than 12% of the United States' population is living with a disability. Disabilities can include vision difficulties, hearing difficulties, mobility challenges, and much more.  And a person can become disabled at any stage of their life.  Since a significant portion of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Bullet Points – How to Create an Unordered List with the &lt;ul&gt; Tag Example]]></title>
        <id>6155b8f964aefe07d3fa1234</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-bullet-points-how-to-create-an-unordered-list-with-the-ul-tag-example/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T17:31:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We use lists all the time in our everyday lives.  We create them to structure and organize our days, and we use them to make to-do lists. We use them in recipes so we don't miss any of the steps. And we use them when we want to assemble a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SQL Distinct Statement – How to Query, Select, and Count]]></title>
        <id>613f3c6d852f4307d372c7ca</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/sql-distinct-statement-how-to-query-select-and-count/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T16:24:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In SQL, you can make a database query and use the COUNT function to get the number of rows for a particular group in the table.  In this article, I will show you how to use the COUNT function with a few code examples.  What is the COUNT function in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git for Professionals – Free Version Control Course]]></title>
        <id>6155d5c364aefe07d3fa1467</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/git-for-professionals/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T15:29:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost every software developer uses git. Many use it continually throughout the day. While you may already know the very basics of git, your productivity will be increased if you learn some advanced git concepts. We just released a git course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating the Perfect Commit in Git]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352475</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-the-perfect-commit-in-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T14:29:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A commit can be something that helps us stay on top of things. It can be a container for related changes that belong to one and only one topic, and thereby make it easier for us to understand what happened.
In this post, we’re talking about what it takes to produce the "perfect" commit.
The post Creating the Perfect Commit in Git appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Günther</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing HTML Preprocessor Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=350620</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/comparing-html-preprocessor-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(This is a sponsored post.)
Of the languages that browsers speak, I’d wager that the very first one that developers decided needed some additional processing was HTML. Every single CMS in the world (aside from intentionally headless-only CMSs) …
The post Comparing HTML Preprocessor Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Time Of Transition (October 2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-october-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get your desktop ready for fall and the upcoming Halloween season with a fresh batch of desktop wallpapers. Created with love by designers and artists from across the globe, they come in versions with and without a calendar for October 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[为 VMware Fusion 虚拟机添加 TPM 2.0 模块，安装 Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39962</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/vmware-fusion-tpm-2-windows-11/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T07:27:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[对于 VMware Fusion 虚拟机用户，在升级 Windows 11 的时候，肯定会遇到 TPM 2.0 与安全启动的问题，几天前青小蛙分享了：如何将 Windows 11 从传统的 BIOS]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Streams Everywhere (and Fetch for Node.js)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352723</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/web-streams-everywhere-and-fetch-for-node-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T14:51:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome developer advocate Jake Archibald called 2016 “the year of web streams.” Clearly, his prediction was somewhat premature. The Streams Standard was announced back in 2014. It’s taken a while, but there’s now a consistent streaming API implemented …
The post Web Streams Everywhere (and Fetch for Node.js) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Dev Shortcuts in iOS 15]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352627</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-dev-shortcuts-in-ios-15/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T14:51:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was pretty stoked when Chris shared a way to “View Source” on mobile. Sure, it’s not the same as a built-in feature but it allows iOS users like myself a way to peek at a site’s code the …
The post Front-End Dev Shortcuts in iOS 15 appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BitDock – Windows 桌面秒变 Mac 风格]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39946</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/bitdock-for-windows-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T09:57:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BitDock 是一款 Windows 下的桌面美化工具，它可以让你的桌面瞬间变成 Mac 风格，并且支持自定义添加应用、网址、文件夹等启动项，还有日历、时钟、天气等 20＋桌面插件，个性化设置你的专]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Modern Image Formats: AVIF And WebP]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/modern-image-formats-avif-webp/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T08:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll highlight how modern image formats (AVIF or WebP) can improve compression by up to 50% and deliver better quality per-byte while still looking visually appealing. We’ll compare what’s possible at high-quality, low-quality and file-size targets.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[彩色 WorkFlowy 发布，「无限层级笔记」工具终于有颜色了]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39939</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/workflowy-color/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T04:26:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[彩色 WorkFlowy 发布。现在可以轻松为文本和标签添加颜色了。]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[So many little design helper sites!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352669</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/so-many-little-design-helper-sites/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had one of those little single-serving designer helper sites bookmarked the other day: getwaves.io. Randomized SVG waves! Lots of cool options! Easy to customize! Easy to copy and paste! Well played, z creative labs. 

But then I …
The post So many little design helper sites! appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Browser Choice]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352681</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/ios-browser-choice/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:26:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just last week I got one of those really?! 🤨 faces when this fact came up in conversation amongst smart and engaged fellow web developers: there is no browser choice on iOS. It’s all Safari. You can download apps that …
The post iOS Browser Choice appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Unleashed is Back! (Use Coupon Code “CSS-Tricks” for 50% Off)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352073</id>
        <link href="https://fitc.ca/event/webu21/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(This is a sponsored post.)
Now in its tenth year (!!!), Web Unleashed is one of the top events for web devs. It’s coming up quick: October 20-22, 2021. 
The lineup is amazing. You’ll hear from leaders in …
The post Web Unleashed is Back! (Use Coupon Code “CSS-Tricks” for 50% Off) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Accessibility Of Your Markdown]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/improving-accessibility-of-markdown/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can find Markdown in many places on the Internet. This article covers different aspects of Markdown and how it interacts with other technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bili.Uwp – 为 Windows 11 设计，第三方哔哩哔哩 Bilibili 客户端]]></title>
        <id>https://www.appinn.com/?p=39935</id>
        <link href="https://www.appinn.com/bilibili-uwp-third-party-client/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T06:43:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bili.Uwp 这是是一款还在测试中，处于技术预览版的第三方哔哩哔哩 Bilibili 客户端，UWP 应用，专为 Windows 11 设计。界面优美，支持看弹幕、发弹幕，排行榜、热门、分区、直播]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>青小蛙</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tonic (Component Framework)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352621</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/tonic-component-framework/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I enjoy little frameworks like Tonic. It’s essentially syntactic sugar over <web-components /> to make them feel easier to use. Define a Class, template literal an HTML template, probably some other fancy helpers, and you’ve got a component …
The post Tonic (Component Framework) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collecting Email Signups With the Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=352211</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/collecting-email-signups-with-the-notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of people these days are setting up their own newsletters. You’ve got the current big names like Substack and MailChimp, companies like Twitter are getting into it with Revue, and even Facebook is getting into the …
The post Collecting Email Signups With the Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ravgeet Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s Dive Into Cypress For End-to-End Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/cypress-end-to-end-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is end-to-end testing a painful topic for you? In this article, Ramona Schwering explains how to handle end-to-end testing with Cypress and make it make it not so tedious and expensive for yourself, but fun instead.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ramona Schwering)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebuilding A Large E-Commerce Website With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/lessons-learned-ecommerce-nextjs-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We made the switch from a more traditional integrated e-commerce platform to a headless platform with Next.js. Here are the most important lessons learned while rebuilding a large e-commerce site with Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jonne Kats)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Online Workshop: Frustrating Design Patterns And How To Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/smashing-workshop-frustrating-design-patterns/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T06:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve seen them before. Confusing and frustrating design patterns that seem to be chasing you everywhere you go, from one website to another. It’s time to fix them for good in a [free Smashing online workshop](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/workshops/vitaly-friedman-frustrating-patterns/) next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying Form Styles With `accent-color`]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/simplifying-form-styles-accent-color/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new CSS `accent-color` property makes it quick and easy to roll out our brand colors to certain form inputs by leveraging user agent styles. In this article we’ll take a look at what it does and how to use it alongside `color-scheme` for simple, accessible checkboxes and radio buttons — and imagine how we might use it in the future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Michelle Barker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Your `head` Straight: A New CSS Performance Diagnostics Snippet]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/css-head-tag/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We love little useful tools and techniques to help folks get their work done better and faster. Today, we’d love to shine the spotlights on a little helper that helps spot common performance bottlenecks easily: [ct.css](https://csswizardry.com/ct/).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build Your Own Mouseless Development Environment]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/mouseless-development-environment/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a development environment with the shell as a keystone offers multiple benefits. You can customize everything depending on your own needs, and the biggest of all, you can control your entire development environment with your keyboard.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matthieu Cneude)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Web Development Tools Are Helping Users Keep Pace With Rapid Change]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-development-tools-users-keep-pace-rapid-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last 18 months have been a time of unprecedented turbulence. As the people of the world have flooded online, businesses have joined them, using web development tools to adapt in real-time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Imposter Domains Re-Publishing Your Website?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/imposter-domains-republishing-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content scraping is a fact of life on the Internet. When you think of web scraping, you probably do not think about the scrapers turning around and immediately serving your entire, whole page content on another website. But what if your site content is being re-published?  It might be already happening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ken Harker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monetize Open-Source Software With Gatsby Functions And Stripe]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/monetize-open-source-software-gatsby-functions-stripe/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/monetize-open-source-software-gatsby-functions-stripe/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gatsby Functions provide front-end developers a way to write and use server-side code without the hassle of maintaining a server. If making money from open-source is of interest to you and your site isn’t built using Gatsby, this approach may well be the answer you were looking for.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Paul Scanlon)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Quality Assurance: From User Requirements To Web Risk Management]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/journey-into-web-quality-assurance/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/journey-into-web-quality-assurance/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty years ago, Elie Sloïm chose to dedicate his professional life to web quality assurance. He started asking, ”What does quality mean for a web user?” Well, this article explains everything he has learned along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Elie Sloïm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons To Build A CRM-Powered Website For Your Business]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reasons-build-crm-powered-website-business/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reasons-build-crm-powered-website-business/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating a CRM with your business website has numerous benefits. In this article, Zara Cooper explains what these benefits are and why websites should be integrated with a CRM platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Zara Cooper)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing The Need For Pseudo-Elements]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reducing-need-pseudo-elements/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/reducing-need-pseudo-elements/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years, pseudo-elements have faithfully helped front-end developers implement creative designs. While they still have an important place, we can now leave pseudo-elements behind in some scenarios, thanks to newer CSS properties.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Marcel Moreau)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Power Of Pen And Paper Sketching]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/power-pen-paper-sketching/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/power-pen-paper-sketching/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When designing for digital spaces, it’s natural to default to digital mockup tools, but doing so cuts out a world of possibilities. Analog drawing can unleash your imagination and allow you to focus on what’s most important at the start: the ideas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tracy Osborn)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orchestrating Complexity With Web Animations API]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/orchestrating-complexity-web-animations-api/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/orchestrating-complexity-web-animations-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are way too many options in Web Animations API to pick them up that easily. Learning how timing works and how to control the playback of several animations at once makes for a solid foundation on which to base your projects on.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kirill Myshkin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Excellent Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-design-done-well-excellent-editorial/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/web-design-done-well-excellent-editorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They say content is king, and they’re right. The web has unlocked untold possibilities for storytellers — provided the story is right, of course. Here are some of our favorite examples of editorial content thriving in the digital realm.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using SWR React Hooks With Next.js’ Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/useswr-react-hook-library-incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/useswr-react-hook-library-incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When paired with ISR and Next.js’ API routes, SWR can be used to create a responsive user experience. In this article, Sam Poder explains what SWR is, where to use it (and where not), and how to build a website by using Incremental Static Regeneration.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Sam Poder)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Decisions For Building Flexible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/developer-decisions-building-flexible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/developer-decisions-building-flexible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll walk through the process of taking a seemingly simple design for a text-and-media component and deciding how best to translate it into code, keeping in mind the needs of both users and content authors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Michelle Barker)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Smashing Online Workshops on Front-End & UX]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/new-smashing-online-workshops-sep-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/new-smashing-online-workshops-sep-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What’s the state of HTML Email, Vue.js and Next.js? What are new, smart interface design patterns we could use? Let’s figure it out. With our brand new online workshops on front-end & design. Now with **free workshops** for you to test the waters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s New With DevTools: Cross-Browser Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/devtools-cross-browser-edition/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/devtools-cross-browser-edition/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn what’s new with developer tools in Firefox, Edge, Chrome and Safari. Discover new and powerful features that will help you be more comfortable and productive when testing and debugging across browsers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Patrick Brosset)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTTP/3: Practical Deployment Options (Part 3)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/http3-practical-deployment-options-part3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/09/http3-practical-deployment-options-part3/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After almost five years in development, the new HTTP/3 protocol is nearing its final form. Let’s take a close look at the challenges involved in deploying and testing HTTP/3, and how and if you should change your websites and resources as well.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Robin Marx)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>