<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html</id>
    <title>gsyx::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-05-27T11:29:38.406Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Blockchain, Solidity, and Full Stack JavaScript Development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-blockchain-solidity-full-stack-javascript-development/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-blockchain-solidity-full-stack-javascript-development/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are thousands of open jobs related to blockchain development companies like IBM, VMware, and Deloitte. We just published a 30-hour course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help you learn skills related to blockchain, Solidity, and Web3 development. If you are interested in learning about blockchain development, this]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript String.Split() Example with RegEx]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-string-split-example-with-regex/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-string-split-example-with-regex/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In JavaScript, you use RegEx to match patterns in characters. Combining this with the .split() string method gives you more splitting powers. The string constructor has many useful methods [https://dillionmegida.com/p/10-useful-string-methods-in-javascript/], one of which is the split() method. You use this method to split a string into an array of substrings]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dillion Megida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use PyScript – A Python Frontend Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pyscript-python-front-end-framework/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pyscript-python-front-end-framework/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:37:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python has grown in popularity immensely in recent years. It has a wide range of applications, from its most popular use in Artificial Intelligence, to Data Science, Robotics, and Scripting.  In the web development field, Python is used mainly on the backend with frameworks such as Django and Flask.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ifihanagbara Olusheye</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lexical Scope in JavaScript – Beginner's Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lexical-scope-in-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lexical-scope-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we are going to understand what lexical scope is by going through some helpful examples.  We will also have a brief discussion about how JavaScript compiles and executes programs.  Lastly, we will have a look at how you can use lexical scope to explain undeclared]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keyur Paralkar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intermediate TypeScript and React Handbook – How to Build Strongly Typed Polymorphic Components]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-components-with-react-and-typescript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-components-with-react-and-typescript/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T14:49:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! 😎 In this detailed guide, I’ll show you how to build strongly typed Polymorphic React components with Typescript. If you prefer to read the entire guide in a single PDF document, you can download the accompanying free PDF [https://www.ohansemmanuel.com/books/how-to-build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-react-components] . You can download the eBook for free [https://www.ohansemmanuel.com/books/how-to-build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-react-components]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emmanuel Ohans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Code a Framework – the  First Lines of Vue.js]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-code-a-framework-vuejs-example/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-code-a-framework-vuejs-example/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:38:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how frameworks are built? A couple of weeks ago I was writing an article and asked myself, what's the first line of code Evan You wrote to build Vue.js? Well, thanks to Git and Evan You pushing Vue's code to GitHub, I have been able to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Pacific</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Emoji – How to Use Twemoji on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-twitter-emoji-on-your-website/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-twitter-emoji-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll explain what Twitter Emoji – or Twemoji – are and why you might want to use them. Why should you use Twitter Emojis? A couple of months ago, I started working on a project of mine, and I needed to allow users to select different icons]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shayan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Test React Applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-test-react-applications/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-test-react-applications/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T16:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React is one of the most popular frontend JavaScript frameworks. If you want to make sure that your React apps work as intended, it is important to write comprehensive tests. We just published a React testing course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to build, deploy,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Grid Layout – Grid Properties Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-css-grid-layout/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-css-grid-layout/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T15:32:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever had a problem positioning items on your web browser? Perhaps every time you try to think of a solution, you become tired and give up.  If so, stay tuned as I reveal a new method for resolving these kinds of problems with minimal or no stress.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okoro Emmanuel Nzube</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Promises for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-for-beginners/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T14:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In JavaScript, a promise is a placeholder (proxy) for the value of an ongoing operation. You typically use a promise to manage situations where you must wait for the outcome of an operation. For example, uploading files to the server and awaiting the response of an API call, or just]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Spruce Emmanuel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>