<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html</id>
    <title>gsyx::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-05-27T11:41:01.329Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://gsyx666.github.io/action-osmosfeed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardstuck Fresh Graduate]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/sem1colons/hardstuck-fresh-graduate-5ecp</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/sem1colons/hardstuck-fresh-graduate-5ecp"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T11:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm 1 month away from graduating with a BSc in software engineering. I've always seen myself as a freelance developer but that is kinda hard to start with and even if I wanted to work with a company, their demands will be 1yr experience at minimum.
Although I don't have that much of professional work experience, I`ve done a few projects that verifies my skills.
The question is how can I start my freelance career(or corporate career) giving that internship opportunities hardly exist in my country (Egypt) and nearly everyone want seniors with 5+ yrs. It`s really disappointing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Youssef Abdulaziz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Junior Developer]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/glowreeyah/dear-junior-developer-4he</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/glowreeyah/dear-junior-developer-4he"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T10:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Junior Developer,
When starting out in tech, understand that your work or what you've built won't be perfect. Hence, when you outgrow every stage, you'd always look back and see the mistakes you made starting out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Glowreeyah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI for Sales]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/ochwada/ai-for-sales-d9m</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/ochwada/ai-for-sales-d9m"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T10:16:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smart technology has revolutionised the world as we know it and gets smarter with each passing hour; where do salespersons stand? How is technology changing the way salespeople do business?  What are the unseen consequences in sales or business if salespersons do not adapt to the Fourth Industrial Revolution? Like many other industries, the world of sales and marketing is experiencing a significant change - ‘tectonic shifts. Thanks to the cutting edge digital infrastructure, Artificial Intelligence (one of the advances of the Fourth Industrial Revolution) has a global footprint, I.e. in every industry. According to a study conducted by Harvard Business Review, companies using AI in sales increased their leads by more than 50%, reduced call time by 60-70 %, and realised cost reductions of 4…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ochwada Linda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AWS open source news and updates, #114]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/aws/aws-open-source-news-and-updates-114-51ng</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/aws/aws-open-source-news-and-updates-114-51ng"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[May 27th, 2022 - Instalment #114


Welcome to the AWS open source newsletter #114. This weeks new open source projects feature a variety of community related projects such as "instance-scheduler" a tool to help you schedule AWS resources, "libaws" an opinionated tool that helps you simplify creation and deletion of some AWS resources, "elasticspot" a nice tool to help you reassign elastic IPs, and "auto-close-aws-accounts" that allows you to close AWS accounts if you are using AWS Organisations. We have plenty of other projects such as "amazon-ec2-spot-interrupter" a nice tool that provides a command line tool to trigger spot interruption notifications, and others that help you work with AWS Glue, simplify deployments of SageMaker notebooks, and others. 
Also featured are blog posts coveri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ricardo Sueiras</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top DevOps Announcement from Microsoft Build 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/n3wt0n/top-devops-announcement-from-ms-build-2022-5fcp</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/n3wt0n/top-devops-announcement-from-ms-build-2022-5fcp"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:48:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Build 2022 has just closed its virtual doors, with a lot of new services and features, and this time around a lot has been said also about DevOps.
Today I’m going to recap all the most important announcements around DevOps made by Microsoft at Build 2002
As usual, if you are a visual learner, or simply prefer to watch and listen instead of reading, here you have the video with the whole explanation and demo, which to be fair is much more complete than this post.




Link to the video: https://youtu.be/Lq0BPwa69C8
If you rather prefer reading, well... let's just continue :)
Let’s start not with an announcement but rather with a lack thereof, with the great absent at Build 2022: I’m talking about Azure DevOps.
There were in fact a lot of announcements and sessions revolving around …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Davide 'CoderDave' Benvegnù</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What people think that web developers do vs. what we really do]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/codepo8/what-people-think-that-web-developers-do-vs-what-we-really-do-12p0</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/codepo8/what-people-think-that-web-developers-do-vs-what-we-really-do-12p0"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:06:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What people think web developers do:



Code, deploy and use, with coding being the main task

Coding
Require random 3rd party framework code
Updating Node/NPM
Try the last command again with sudo

Checking on mobile
Shaking fist towards Cupertino
Looking things up on the web
Pasting Stack Overflow solutions
Resize the browser/use emulation
Discover that a browser extension was the problem all along
Explain again that things can't look the same everywhere
Add ARIA till everything is fine
Trace performance issues back to analytics/ad code
Convert content to usable formats
Adding/Removing console.log()
Invalidate caches
Using
Summon Imhotep using blood magic to help with a rendering bug]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Heilmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week in Python]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/bascodes/this-week-in-python-4859</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/bascodes/this-week-in-python-4859"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:02:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fri, May 27, 2022
This Week in Python is a concise reading list about what happened in the past week in the Python universe. 
@bascodes
      
Here are some great articles and interesting projects I found #ThisWeekInPython 🐍
👇
    
Python Standard Library changes in recent years – How the Python std lib changed with the last Python versions
Contributing to open source – Rodrigo started contributing to open source
25 Python Projects for Beginners
Multitenancy with FastAPI
Memory Management in Python – First part of a series about memory management in CPython
rounder – Python package for rounding floats and complex numbers in complex Python objects
Pants – A video filter to add pants or blur out your lower half on Zoom calls when you forget to wear pants
tetra – A full stack component framework for Django using Alpine.js – by @samwillis
cog – Micro Graph Database for Python Applications – 
dotdrop – Save your dotfiles once, deploy them everywhere]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bas codes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop putting AWS credentials in the credentials file]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/aws-builders/stop-putting-aws-credentials-in-the-credentials-file-3f7e</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/aws-builders/stop-putting-aws-credentials-in-the-credentials-file-3f7e"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T08:37:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Ben Kehoe thread to an OSS tool for the on-demand credentials generation


To me, Everything started with this Twitter thread and from that article, by Ben Kehoe:
 
When dealing with CLI or SDKs, we are already used to putting IAM credentials in the .aws/credentials file.
However, as correctly stated cluttering the credentials file with many credentials is not the right move to make.
This article aims to overview what IAM Principals are and the better ways to manage your programmatic access to AWS.
Moreover, we'll focus on the Credential Process. We'll see that we can polish our local usage of AWS Principals with it.
Let's dig into this journey through AWS authorization systems.
Stating the official documentation: "A principal is a person or application that can request an action or o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandro Gaggia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now I'm here - 5 years badge on dev.to. Where were you 5 years ago ? :)]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/piotroxp/now-im-here-5-years-badge-on-devto-where-were-you-5-years-ago--23b7</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/piotroxp/now-im-here-5-years-badge-on-devto-where-were-you-5-years-ago--23b7"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T07:59:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What were you doing 5 years ago?


I recently got a notification about my 5 years on dev.to. It hit me really hard, as I was not active here once I switched careers from scientist to software engineer. 
Back then, dev.to was a startup, I was amidst going from being a Technology Wizard at a high tech perovskite solar cell technology company towards my own startup, which is kinda in zombie state now - we did invent smart functional materials that can be used for a Black Panther suit, amongst other things. 
Some year later, I was freelancing and looking for a job. 3 and a half years ago, landed my current job. Now - I'm here.
Whats your story?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Piotr Słupski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Mistakes to Avoid When Starting a SideProject]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/ranuzz/common-mistakes-to-avoid-when-starting-a-sideproject-237j</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/ranuzz/common-mistakes-to-avoid-when-starting-a-sideproject-237j"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T07:36:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time estimation in software engineering seems to be the most difficult task.
Time estimation becomes a bit easier for well-managed projects where most of the design decisions have been made and there is enough internal tooling and resources. But it is still not perfect. Things become more difficult for teams with limited resources and external pressure on deadlines. More often than not, the projects get delivered, some more polished than others.
When it comes to time estimation, solo developers working on their side projects face a real challenge. It becomes worse if there is no external motivation or revenue potential for the project. Building something for fun or learning might end up in an unfinished project that never sees a launch day.
Side projects should be straightforward by design…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shekhar Chandra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best way to learn Java in easy way]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/deepakguptacoder/best-way-to-learn-java-in-easy-way-118a</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/deepakguptacoder/best-way-to-learn-java-in-easy-way-118a"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T07:24:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[what should I know before learning Java


Well, it doesn’t really matter at all , if you’re interested enough you can directly give it a start with java . However having a prior knowledge of basic OOP’s concepts and a little programming experience(or basic programming concepts) would help you to understand it better and make it easier . Though not mandatory , but to have a strong grip over the concepts before switching to java you can go with C/ C++ ( suggesting as I started with C++ and it has helped me a lot to understand java better)

I am also a java learner but i would like to answer your question. Here all important tips are already given but i want to add only one more point which is much important. 
If you are a beginner, please don't use any kind of IDE.
 IDE is specially made for those who already a pretty decent experienced in programming. 
It is helpful for them who are in a very big project development. I would recommend to use notepad and command prompt as a beginner. 
As using this you have nothing to help you except the internet articles. 
So you can rectify your error yourself. In this way you have gain also a decent experience while learning. 
This learning method is slow but very effective. 
Although you have to use IDE in your future but you will have a good ability to rectify your mistakes. 
You can gain a good idea of what type error comes for what kind of mistakes.


  
  
  Conclusion



  
  
  I hope you found this article useful, if you need any help please let me know in the comment section.💯]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deepak Gupta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 VSCode Extensions You Must Use]]></title>
        <id>https://dev.to/murtuzaalisurti/5-vscode-extensions-you-must-use-961</id>
        <link href="https://dev.to/murtuzaalisurti/5-vscode-extensions-you-must-use-961"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T07:13:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are the 5 most useful Visual Studio Code extensions to improve your workflow!
Error Lens
CSS Peek
GitLens
Import Cost
Version Lens
Error Lens is an extension which allows you to see error, warning and diagnostic messages in line with your code without having to hover or click on anything! It also highlights the line with different colors to help you better visualize and differentiate between errors, warnings and other messages!

With this extension, you can search for relevant CSS files by using CSS classes in html file and edit CSS files there itself! Here's how it works:

GitLens is a powerful extension which can display when a particular line was committed, by whom it was committed and in which pull request it was included along with the commit message! All of this information is inline with the line upon which your cursor is currently located.
You can also hover over the message to get even more information about a particular line of code!


There are many more features in GitLens which you can explore and play around with!
Import Cost allows us to see the size of the imported package inline in the editor itself!

Version Lens fetches information about dependency versions and displays it on top of the package!

These were the 5 VSCode extensions which are powerful, useful and can improve your productivity and workflow!
Signing off.
Twitter | GitHub | LinkedIn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Murtuzaali Surti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Blockchain, Solidity, and Full Stack JavaScript Development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-blockchain-solidity-full-stack-javascript-development/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-blockchain-solidity-full-stack-javascript-development/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are thousands of open jobs related to blockchain development companies like IBM, VMware, and Deloitte. We just published a 30-hour course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help you learn skills related to blockchain, Solidity, and Web3 development. If you are interested in learning about blockchain development, this]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript String.Split() Example with RegEx]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-string-split-example-with-regex/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-string-split-example-with-regex/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In JavaScript, you use RegEx to match patterns in characters. Combining this with the .split() string method gives you more splitting powers. The string constructor has many useful methods [https://dillionmegida.com/p/10-useful-string-methods-in-javascript/], one of which is the split() method. You use this method to split a string into an array of substrings]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dillion Megida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use PyScript – A Python Frontend Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pyscript-python-front-end-framework/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pyscript-python-front-end-framework/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:37:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python has grown in popularity immensely in recent years. It has a wide range of applications, from its most popular use in Artificial Intelligence, to Data Science, Robotics, and Scripting.  In the web development field, Python is used mainly on the backend with frameworks such as Django and Flask.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ifihanagbara Olusheye</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lexical Scope in JavaScript – Beginner's Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lexical-scope-in-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lexical-scope-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we are going to understand what lexical scope is by going through some helpful examples.  We will also have a brief discussion about how JavaScript compiles and executes programs.  Lastly, we will have a look at how you can use lexical scope to explain undeclared]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keyur Paralkar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intermediate TypeScript and React Handbook – How to Build Strongly Typed Polymorphic Components]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-components-with-react-and-typescript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-components-with-react-and-typescript/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T14:49:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone! 😎 In this detailed guide, I’ll show you how to build strongly typed Polymorphic React components with Typescript. If you prefer to read the entire guide in a single PDF document, you can download the accompanying free PDF [https://www.ohansemmanuel.com/books/how-to-build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-react-components] . You can download the eBook for free [https://www.ohansemmanuel.com/books/how-to-build-strongly-typed-polymorphic-react-components]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emmanuel Ohans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Code a Framework – the  First Lines of Vue.js]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-code-a-framework-vuejs-example/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-code-a-framework-vuejs-example/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:38:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how frameworks are built? A couple of weeks ago I was writing an article and asked myself, what's the first line of code Evan You wrote to build Vue.js? Well, thanks to Git and Evan You pushing Vue's code to GitHub, I have been able to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Pacific</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Emoji – How to Use Twemoji on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-twitter-emoji-on-your-website/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-twitter-emoji-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T21:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll explain what Twitter Emoji – or Twemoji – are and why you might want to use them. Why should you use Twitter Emojis? A couple of months ago, I started working on a project of mine, and I needed to allow users to select different icons]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shayan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Test React Applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-test-react-applications/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-test-react-applications/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T16:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React is one of the most popular frontend JavaScript frameworks. If you want to make sure that your React apps work as intended, it is important to write comprehensive tests. We just published a React testing course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to build, deploy,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Grid Layout – Grid Properties Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-css-grid-layout/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-css-grid-layout/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T15:32:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever had a problem positioning items on your web browser? Perhaps every time you try to think of a solution, you become tired and give up.  If so, stay tuned as I reveal a new method for resolving these kinds of problems with minimal or no stress.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okoro Emmanuel Nzube</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Promises for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-for-beginners/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T14:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In JavaScript, a promise is a placeholder (proxy) for the value of an ongoing operation. You typically use a promise to manage situations where you must wait for the outcome of an operation. For example, uploading files to the server and awaiting the response of an API call, or just]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Spruce Emmanuel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>